ilona-andrews.com 2019-05-31

# Privacy Policy

Our website address is: http://www.ilona-andrews.com. This website is owned by Ilona Andrews, Inc.

Your personal data is only collected by this website if you choose to fill in any forms on this website.

  * Data entered into the comments forms is held by this website.
  * The contact form on this website is connected to Gmail and Fastmail accounts, so if you complete it, your data will be shared with Gmail and Fastmail email services.
  * The email sign-up form on this website is connected to a MailChimp account, so if you complete it, your data will be shared with MailChimp.

You can read Gmail’s Privacy Policy in full here: [policies.google.com/privacy](https://policies.google.com/privacy)

You can read Fastmail’s Privacy Policy in full here: <https://www.fastmail.com/about/privacy.html>

You can read MailChimp’s Privacy Policy in full here: [mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/)

Any other data collected about you is only available to the end user (the owner of this website) in an anonymised form, for example, as visitor stats.

No data from this website is downloaded by the owner of the site and stored outside of the cloud services mentioned above.

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact the website’s owner at this page: [contact](http://www.ilona-andrews.com/contact/).

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

#### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

_What does that mean:_

When you comment on this website, the website stores your comment, your name, and other information you chose to enter into the comment form. By commenting, you are giving us permission to hold on to that information and to display it on the website. We do not do anything with this information. It’s retained solely for the purposes of your comment being displayed.

When you leave a comment, our anti-spam software compares the information, such as IP address or email, to the database of known spammers, and if your comment matches it, it will not be displayed and will be moved to spam or pending folders.  This website uses Antispam Bee to perform this function.  Per Antispam site, Antispam Bee is developed in Europe, does not save private user data and is 100% compliant with GDPR.

Some of you chose to use Gravatar.  Gravatar allows you to upload a picture, which is then used as the little avatar/profile picture when you comment. If you signed up for Gravatar, an anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: <https://automattic.com/privacy/>.

_What does that mean:_

Our website communicates with Gravatar to properly display your picture. This is something that happens without our direct involvement and we do not view or have access to any information that passes in this communication.

#### Media

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

### Contact forms

The contact form on this website is connected to Gmail and Fastmail accounts, so if you complete it, your data will be shared with Gmail and Fastmail email services.

You can read Gmail’s Privacy Policy in full here: [policies.google.com/privacy](https://policies.google.com/privacy)

You can read Fastmail’s Privacy Policy in full here: <https://www.fastmail.com/about/privacy.html>

### Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

## Who we share your data with

This website uses Google Analytics to collect data about demographics of the people who access this website. If you do not want your information collected, Google provides you with a browser addon, which you can download here:  <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>

## How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes. To request deletion of your data, please contact us by filling out the form on this page: [Contact](http://www.ilona-andrews.com/contact/).

## Where we send your data

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.
